Guide to the Eugene L. Armbruster Photograph Collection 1894-1939 PR 81
New-York Historical Society
Eugene L. Armbruster photograph collection
1894-1939
New-York Historical Society
Armbruster, Eugene L., 1865-1943
PR 81
36.5 Linear feet (Ca. 5,000 black and white gelatin silver prints, 5 x 7 in. or smaller. Ca 3,500 acetate negatives, 3.5 x 4.5 in. 1,400 nitrate negatives, 5 x 7 in. 517 glass negatives, 8 x 10 in. or smaller.)
New York photographer and local historian born in Baden-Baden, Germany; emigrated to the United States 1882 and lived in Brooklyn, New York. Armbruster photographed historic houses, churches, streetscapes, and buildings throughout New York City, and some of the images he created served to illustrate pamphlets he wrote on the local history of the area. Prints and negatives related to New York from the Eugene L. Armbruster Photograph Collection have been digitized and are available in the Shelby White and Leon Levy Digital Library.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase, October 21, 1944, November 20, 1944, and February 28, 1945.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in two series:
Series I: Prints
Series II: Negatives
Within each series, materials are divided by format and by size.
Biographical Note
Eugene L. Armbruster (1865 - 1943) was born in Baden-Baden, Germany, and came to the United States in 1882. His first job was with H. Henkel Cigar Box Manufacturing Company, where he continued to work until his retirement in 1920. He lived in Bushwick, Brooklyn, with his wife and two children, Julia and Eugene Jr.
Armbruster took photographs beginning in the late 19th century, but the majority of his work is from the 1910s and 1920s. Around the time of his retirement, Armbruster became interested in local history and began to photograph his environs in earnest, specifically the boroughs of Brooklyn and Queens. He took thousands of photographs of historic houses, churches, streetscapes, and buildings throughout New York City and Long Island.
Beginning around 1915, Armbruster wrote for the "Old-Timer" column of the Brooklyn Eagle. He honed his knowledge of local history through reading and extensive walking throughout the streets he was documenting. A majority of his photographs are annotated with historical information. He sought the rural environments linked to the past, turning to the rural counties of Long Island after the towns and neighborhoods of Brooklyn and Queens started growing and modernizing in the early 1920s. From 1914 to 1929, Armbruster published several pamphlets about local history, which he illustrated with his own line drawings, copy photos, and original photographs. In the 1930s, he published three pamphlets on language and its origins, seemingly a new interest.
He was forced to give up photography around 1940 after he developed cataracts on his eyes. He died on September 21, 1943.
Related Materials
The following 10 pamphlets written and/or published by Armbruster are held in The New-York Historical Society Library:
Bruijkleen Colonie. New York, 1918.
Coney Island. New York: [Armbruster], 1924.
The Eastern district of Brooklyn; with illustrations and maps. New York [Printed by G. Quattlander], 1912.
The Ferry road on Long Island. New York [Printed by G. Quattlander], 1919.
Long Island landmarks. New York, 1923.
The Indians of New England and New Netherland. [Brooklyn, N.Y.: Quattlander], 1918.
Marriages of Long Island settlers and allied families. Jamaica, N.Y.: Queens Borough Public Library, 1941.
Montauk. New York: [s.n.], c. 1923.
The Olympia settlement in early Brooklyn. N.Y. New York, 1929.
The Wallabout prison ships. New York, 1920.
The New York Public Library, Brooklyn Historical Society, and Queens Borough Public Library all hold extensive Armbruster photograph and ephemera (pamphlets, scrapbooks, papers) collections.
Scope and Contents
The Eugene L. Armbruster Photograph Collection includes approximately 5,000 black and white gelatin silver prints, approximately 3,500 acetate film negatives; approximately 1,400 nitrate film negatives; four 4 x 5" glass negatives; 235 5 x 7" glass negatives; 230 6.5 x 8.5" glass negatives; and 48 8 x 10" glass negatives.
The collection spans the period from 1894-1939 and contains photographic views of New York State, Pennsylvania, New Jersey, New England, and Canada. Most of the photographs show New York City, especially Brooklyn, Queens, and Long Island. These images document many structures that no longer exist, and in some cases may be the only extant photographic record. The collection is arranged into two series based on format: Prints and Negatives. The prints and negatives have not been matched to each other, although there are most likely many corresponding positives and negatives in the collection. Within each series, subseries are arranged by size or material, and thereunder alphabetically by state, and then by. Within New York State, the photos of New York City and Long Island are divided into county and then by neighborhood.
Series I. Prints is divided into the following subseries: Prints: 3.5 x 4.5" (and smaller); Prints: 5 x 7"; and Mounted Prints. Most prints are annotated in some manner on the verso. Some prints have Armbruster's map on the verso, showing the exact location of the building/house. Often he has included historical information on the house or building and in some cases he has added notes such as "still standing 1929."
The majority of photographs were taken after Armbruster's retirement in 1920. Earlier photographs are generally of New York City or nearby counties in New Jersey. With time on his hands, Armbruster traveled out of New York City, and those trips are well documented here. In July, 1925, for example, Armbruster traveled throughout New York State, New England, and Canada. It is notable that these photographs reflect only historic buildings and sites, not family or leisure shots.
Many of the Brooklyn and Queens photos (and all of the 5 x 7" prints) date from 1922. Most of the subjects no longer exist, mainly due to a building boom in the boroughs in the late 1920s. In some cases Armbruster seems to have been aware of demolition plans, and photographed houses for just that reason. The views of Brooklyn are also notable for their almost exclusive focus on historical sites and subjects. Other photographs of the borough from a similar time period often show modern improvements, such as elevated rail tracks, automobiles, industry and skyscrapers. Armbruster organized his Brooklyn photos in groups according to the six original towns in the county: Brooklyn, Bushwick, Flatbush, Flatlands, Gravesend and New Utrecht.
Notable Brooklyn structures pictured include Holland School, Lefferts Farm, and Packer Collegiate Institute. Other commercial buildings shown are grocery stores, engine houses, gymnasiums, banks, hotels, cigar stores, a tollhouse on Flatbush Avenue, florists, and a blacksmith and wheelwright shop.
Brooklyn residences include the homes of the following notable Brooklyn residents: Treadwell Abrams, Wynant Bennett, Fenwick Bergen, Jeremiah Bergen, John L. Bergen; Horace B. Claflin, Samuel Coland, Charles Ekoch, Joseph Fleming, John Franklin, Joseph Golden, Joseph Herrings, John F. James, Horatio King, Johannes Lott, Judge Ganet L. Martense, Henry Evelyn Pierrepont (1808-1888), W. A. Putnam, Derick Remsen, Johannes Remsen, James S. Rockwell, John J. Ryder, John F. Ryerson, John Schenk, Moses Snydaw, David D. Stillwell, Colonel David M. Stone (1817-1895), Charles Strohm, Spencer Trask, Rutgert Joosten Van Brunt, John H. Van Cleef, John L. Van Pelt, John J. Vanderbilt (d. 1842), Daniel D. Whitney, Lionel Wilbur, and Garrett Williams.
Churches in Brooklyn shown include: Central Presbyterian Church, Church of the New Jerusalem, Emanuel Protestant Episcopal Church, First Presbyterian Church, First Unitarian Church of Our Savior, Grace Church, Holy Cross Roman Catholic Church, New Utrecht Reformed Dutch Church, Plymouth Church, Reform Church on the Heights, St. John's Lutheran Church, St. Patrick's Roman Catholic Church, and St. Paul's Episcopal Church.
Series II. Negatives is arranged in five subseries: Acetate Film Negatives: 4 x 5"; Nitrate Film Negatives: 5 x 7"; Glass Plate Negatives: 5 x 7" (and smaller); Glass Plate Negatives: 6.5 x 8.5"; and Glass Plate Negatives: 8 x 10".
Negatives are arranged by geographic location, if known, as described above. Subject terms found in the Thesaurus for Graphic Material (Library of Congress: 1995) have been utilized to further organize negatives beyond geographical divisions. Photograph topics fall into the following categories: architectural elements, automobiles, barns, boats, buildings, churches, dams, farmhouses, interiors, landscapes, people, row houses, streets, and windmills.
Featured buildings in Subseries IV: Glass Plate Negatives: 6.5 x 8.5," include: the Abbey Pub, the Brooklyn Bridge, Brooklyn Waterworks, the Bushwick Hospital, Federal Courts Building, Fort Greene Tobacco Works, Mansion House, the Packer Collegiate Institute, and Underhill's Colonnade Buildings (on edge of Brooklyn Heights). Other commercial buildings shown are hotels, a horse-shoeing shop, ferry terminals, flour mills, printing offices, public school, race courses, a saw manufacturer, and several theaters. Among the churches shown are: Bushwick Church, First Reformed Church, Grace Church, New Utrecht Church, Old Assumption Church, Old St. Ann's Protestant Episcopal Church, Plymouth Church, St. James Roman Catholic Church, and St. Mark's Episcopal Church.
Houses shown in Subseries IV include those of: Thomas Bennett; Dewitt Clinton; Seth Low, mayor of Brooklyn and New York City; the Schermerhorn family; the Van Brunt family; and Mayor (of Williamsburgh) William Wall. Other views of interest are: a circular, dated October 1, 1869, announcing the opening of Wechsler and Abraham Clothing Store; the City of Williamsburgh Seal; and an October 3, 1860 Brooklyn survey map.
Separated Materials
Subseries II, Nitrate Film Negatives: 5 x 7", has been separated from the rest of the Eugene L. Armbruster Collection. Nitrate negatives are not housed in the Print Room due to potential storage hazards; all nitrate negatives are stored on Floor 14 of the N-YHS Library stacks. Please ask a staff member for assistance with these negatives.
Acetate film.; Glass negatives.; negatives (photographs); Photographic prints.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; New England -- Pictorial works.; Long Island (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Nassau County (N.Y.); New York (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.; Niagara Falls (N.Y. and Ont.); Queens (New York, N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Suffolk County (N.Y.)
- Series I: Prints
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I is divided into the following subseries: Prints: 3.5 x 4.5" (and smaller); Prints: 5 x 7"; and Mounted Prints. Each subseries has been arranged by state, and thereunder by county and town.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Digital copies of prints related to New York are available in the Shelby White and Leon Levy Digital Library.
  - Subseries I: Prints: 3.5 x 4.5" (and smaller)
    Subseries I is about evenly split between scenes of New England and those of New York. Most of these prints are annotated by Armbruster. Some annotations include supplementary information, such as the population of Hampshire County, Massachusetts. Two small postcard sets ("tour cards") of Philadelphia and Williamsport, Pennsylvania are included.
    - Connecticut--Fairfield County, 1927 Jul. (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Connecticut--Hartford County, 1926-1927 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Connecticut--New Haven County, 1927 Jul. (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Connecticut--New London County, 1923-1927 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Maine--Androscan County, 1926 Aug. (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Maine--Cumberland County, 1926 Aug. (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Maine--Hancock County, 1923 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Maine--Knox County, 1923 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Maine--York County, 1926 Aug. (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Maine--Unidentified, undated (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Massachusetts--Barnstable County, 1925 Oct. (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Massachusetts--Berkshire County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Massachusetts--Essex County, 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Massachusetts--Franklin County, 1928-1935 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Massachusetts--Hampton County, 1926-1930 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Massachusetts--Hampshire County, 1925-1929 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Massachusetts--Middlesex County, 1926-1928 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Massachusetts--Suffolk County, 1925-1930 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - Massachusetts--Worcester County, 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - New Hampshire--Belknap County, 1929 May (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - New Hampshire--Carroll County, 1926 Aug. (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - New Hampshire--Cheshire County, 1925-1927 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - New Hampshire--Coos County, 1926-1929 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - New Hampshire--Hillsborough County, 1928-1930 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - New Hampshire--Merrimack County, 1926-1929 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - New Hampshire--Rockingham County, 1928-1929 (Offsite-box 1, Box 1)
    - New Hampshire--Strafford County, 1929 May (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New Hampshire--Sullivan County, 1926-1929 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New Hampshire--Unidentified, 1926-1930 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - Massachusetts, New Hampshire or Vermont (unidentified), undated (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New Jersey--Bergen County, 1894-1925 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New Jersey--Essex County, 1929 Aug. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New Jersey--Hudson County, 1897 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New Jersey--Middlesex County, 1923 Aug. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New Jersey--Monmouth County, 1925 Aug. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New Jersey--Morris County, 1929 Aug. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New Jersey--Warren County, 1925-1929 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Albany County, 1926 Jul. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Broome County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Bronx County, 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Clinton County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Columbia County, 1925 Oct. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Delaware County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Dutchess County, 1926-1927 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Essex County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Greene County, 1923 Apr. (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Bushwick, 1897-1924 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatbush, 1895-1926 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatlands, 1915-1925 (Offsite-box 2, Box 2)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Gravesend, 1922-1928 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--New Lots, 1895-1923 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--New Utrecht, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Williamsburg, 1907-1924 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Unidentified, 1922-1925 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Livingston County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--New York County (Manhattan)--Lower East Side and Greenwich Village, 1909-1924 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--New York County (Manhattan)--Unidentified views, 1923-1929 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Nassau County--Hempstead, 1922-1924 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Nassau County--North Hempstead, 1922 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Nassau County--Oyster Bay, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Niagara County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Otsego County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Onandaga County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 3, Box 3)
    - New York--Orleans County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 4, Box 4)
    - New York--Orange County, 1916-1929 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4)
    - New York--Queens County--Flushing, 1922-1924 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4)
    - New York--Queens County--Jamaica, 1895-1935 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4)
    - New York--Queens County--Newtown, 1922-1925 (Offsite-box 4, Box 4)
    - New York--Queens County--Rockaway, 1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Richmond County (Staten Island), 1895-1925 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Rockland County, 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Schuyler County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--St. Lawrence County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Amagansett, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Babylon, 1924 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Bridgehampton, 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Brookhaven, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--East Hampton, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Huntington, 1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Islip, 1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Montauk, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Sagaponick, 1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Shelter Island, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Smithtown, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Southampton, 1922-1924 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Suffolk County--Southold, 1922-1924 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Ulster County, 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Warren County, 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Westchester County, 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Wyoming County, 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - New York--Unidentified, 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Box 5)
    - Pennsylvania--Berks County, 1926 Oct. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Pennsylvania--Carbon County, 1925 Oct. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Pennsylvania--Dauphin County, 1925 Oct. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Pennsylvania--Lehigh County, 1926 Oct. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Pennsylvania--Lycoming County, 1925 Oct. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Pennsylvania--Monroe County, 1925-1929 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Pennsylvania--Northampton County, 1925-1929 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Pennsylvania--Philadelphia County: Philadelphia Tour Cards, undated (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Pennsylvania--Schuylkill County, 1925 Oct. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Pennsylvania--Washington County: Williamsport Tour Cards, undated (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Vermont--Bennington County, 1927 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Vermont--Rutland County, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Vermont--Windham County, 1925-1930 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Vermont--Windsor County, 1926-1927 (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Vermont--Unidentified, undated (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Canada--Greenville-Welland, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Canada--Jacques Cartier, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Canada--La Prairie, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Canada--Lavel, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Canada--Quebec, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Canada--St. Johns, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Canada--Stormant, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
    - Canada--Welland, 1925 Jul. (Offsite-box 6, Box 6)
  - Subseries II: Prints: 5 x 7"
    Subseries II is made up primarily of Brooklyn scenes. The prints are almost all labeled by Armbruster with the names of the original owner of the house, and of the notable people who lived in it; often the exact street address is noted. Armbruster sometimes noted on the back of prints when structures were torn down; most of these semi-rural houses have since been demolished. Neighborhoods (formerly separate towns) are noted, other prints marked "Brooklyn" mainly correspond to downtown Brooklyn and Brooklyn Heights. These prints generally correspond to the 5 x 7" Glass Plate Negatives in Series II, Subseries III, although there are unmatched prints and negatives.
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Brooklyn, 1922 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Bushwick, undated (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatbush, 1922 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatlands, 1898-1922 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Gravesend, 1922-1924 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--New Lots, 1922 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--New Utrecht, 1922 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Nassau County--Hempstead, 1922 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Nassau County--Oyster Bay, 1922 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--New York County (Manhattan), undated (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Queens County--Flushing, 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Queens County--Newtown, 1922-1924 (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Richmond County (Staten Island), 1925 May (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - New York--Westchester County, 1925 May (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
    - Unidentified, undated (Offsite-box 7, Box 7)
  - Subseries III: Mounted Prints
    Box 8 consists of several of the above 5 x 7" prints mounted on board with typed titles. Box 8A contains assorted mounted photographs, including an image of boaters in Prospect Park, a shot of Pierrepont Street in downtown Brooklyn covered in snow, a photo of Midland Beach in Staten Island, Lenox Avenue Bridge, Central Bridge, New York and Putnam Railroad Bridge, and others.
    - Brooklyn, 1921-1923 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8)
    - Manhattan, Brooklyn, Staten Island, undated (Offsite-box 8A, Box 8A)
- Series II: Negatives
  Series II. Negatives is arranged in five subseries: Acetate Film Negatives: 4 x 5"; Nitrate Film Negatives: 5 x 7"; Glass Plate Negatives: 5 x 7" (and smaller); Glass Plate Negatives: 6.5 x 8.5"; and Glass Plate Negatives: 8 x 10".
  Digital copies of negatives related to New York are available in the Shelby White and Leon Levy Digital Library.
  - Subseries I, Acetate Film Negatives: 4 x 5"
    Subseries I is housed in envelopes, which are grouped by geographic region. The number of negatives in each grouping is listed in parentheses after the geographical location. These negatives seem to correspond, however roughly, to groupings of prints in Series I. It is probable that the geographic names found on each envelope were transferred from titles on the original film boxes. These envelopes are numbered; the number seems to correspond to their original physical placement in a cabinet in the N-YHS library stacks.
    - Connecticut (18), undated (Offsite-box 9, Box 9)
    - Maine (72), undated (Offsite-box 9, Box 9)
    - Massachusetts (128), undated (Offsite-box 9, Box 9)
    - Massachusetts and New Hampshire (174), undated (Offsite-box 9, Box 9)
    - New England (419), undated (Offsite-box 9, Box 9)
    - New England (54), undated (Offsite-box 10, Box 10)
    - New Hampshire (211), undated (Offsite-box 10, Box 10)
    - New Jersey (48), undated (Offsite-box 10, Box 10)
    - New York (31), undated (Offsite-box 10, Box 10)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Brooklyn (146), undated (Offsite-box 10, Box 10)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Bushwick (108), undated (Offsite-box 10, Box 10)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatbush (88), undated (Offsite-box 10, Box 10)
    - New York--Kings County (Brooklyn)--Flatbush (53), undated (Offsite-box 11, Box 11)